Guide to the Science, Technology, and Human Values Program records, 1979-1984.
Duke University. University Archives
Science, Technology, and Human Values Program records 1979-1984.
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Science, Technology, and Human Values Program.
0.7 linear feet Extent: 400 Items
The Science, Technology and Human Values program (STHV), formerly known as the Science, Society, and Human Values Program, was begun in 1979 by James F. Gifford and Seymour Mauskopf as a unique interdisciplinary program focused on developing a comprehensive view of science, medicine, and technology in social, historical, and ethical terms. The collection contains director's files from 1979-1984 which include administrative and student correspondence, memoranda, student term papers, course syllabi and evaluations, and five cassette tapes of sessions at a STHV symposium on space travel. The collection also contains brochures for the Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, dated 1976-1983.
RL.01871
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Provenance
The Science, Technology, and Human Values Program records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in July 23, 1992.
Historical Note
The Science, Technology and Human Values program (STHV), formerly known as the Science, Society, and Human Values Program, was begun in 1979 by James F. Gifford and Seymour Mauskopf as a unique interdisciplinary program focused on developing a comprehensive view of science, medicine, and technology in social, historical, and ethical terms. This program, likely influenced by the annual Round Table on Science and Public Affairs held at Duke of which Mauskopf served on the Advisory Committee, sought to educate undergraduate students through a variety of courses in multiple disciplines which culminated in the year-long senior seminar. The program offered monthly dinners, seminars, and panel discussions often with visiting professors on current and emerging issues in science within a societal context. Topics included the expansion of computer use, the role of modern medicine, genetics in humanistic perspective, and worldwide health policies among other things. The program was terminated in 2003.
Collection Overview
The collection contains director's files from 1979-1984 which include administrative and student correspondence, memoranda, grade reports, student term papers, course syllabi and evaluations, and five cassette tapes of sessions at a STHV symposium on space travel. The collection also contains brochures for the Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, dated 1976-1983.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Science, Technology, and Human Values Program; Science -- Moral and ethical aspects; Audiocassettes
Related Material
Inventory of the News Service Biographical Files, circa 1930s – 2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the Thomas E. McCollough Papers, 1965-1997.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Science, Technology, and Human Values Program records, 1979-1984, 1 Box
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs brochures, 1976-1983 (Box 1)
  - Senior Seminar Proposals
  - Senior Seminar "Genetics in Humanistic Perspective," 1979-1980
  - Senior Seminar, 1980
  - Senior Seminar, 1980-1981
  - Senior Seminar, 1981-1982
  - Senior Seminar, 1982-1983
  - Senior Seminar, 1983-1984
  - Correspondence (part 1), 1982-1983
  - Correspondence (part 2), 1982-1983
  - Students Correspondence (part 1), 1980-1983
  - Students Correspondence (part 2), 1980-1983
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Our Future in Space, "What we must Believe to Colonize Space: The Competing Catechisms," Walter McDougall. 18 March 1987. Part 1.
    - Our Future in Space, "What we must Believe to Colonize Space: The Competing Catechisms," Walter McDougall. 18 March 1987. Part 2.
    - Our Future in Space. Robert Jastrow.
    - Our Future in Space. Thomas Gold.
    - Our Future in Space. Hans Mark and Plenary Session.